所以我们采访了前面的工程师。
So we interviewed for front engineers.
这当然是为了奠定基础。
This course is to help
lay that groundwork.
我不能保证到最后我就会回答每一次可能的面试
I can't guarantee by the end, I will have
answered every single possible interview
你会不会在你的生活中出现这种可能性是不可能的
question you will ever get in your life,
that is not possible.
但我能保证你能更好地了解
But what I can guarantee is you're gonna
have a better understanding of what
面试是，应该是什么，专门面向前方的工程师。
interviewing is, and what it should be,
specifically for frontend engineers.
这个过程有点不寻常，因为它是从两部分中得知的。
And this course is a little unusual
because it's told from two parts.
从候选人的角度来看
It's told from
the candidate's perspective.
如果你愿意的话
That would be the interviewee if you will,
but
我喜欢候选人库会有点乱
I like candidate cuz
it'll get a little messy.
它是从这个角度讲的，因为你最了解的是
And it's told from that perspective
because that's the perspective most of you
都是从这来的
are coming from.
你是说我有很多关于面试的焦虑
You're saying, I have a lot of
anxiety about interviewing.
它是任意的，很糟糕，这是一个漫长的过程。
It's arbitrary, it's terrible,
it's a long process.
我想说的是我想说你是怎么处理这些问题的
Yeah, I wanna settle that, I wanna say,
here's how you approach these problems
你也许会看到这里是如何解决这些问题的
that you're probably gonna see and
here's how to solve them.
这就是面试期间的表现
And here's how to behave
during the interview and
这些都是采访的对象
these are the things to
expect from an interview but
一个扭曲的，一个 Jem 的扭曲，有专利，有专利。
a little bit more unusual in a twist,
a Jem twist, patent pending.
我要从一个采访者的角度来回答问题
I'm gonna give the questions from
the perspective of an interviewer.
所以我现在问你，你不用举手，你什么也不用说。
So I ask you now, you don't have to raise
your hand, you don't have to say anything.
但是你花了多少时间去采访人呢 ?
But how much time have you spent
studying how to interview people?
大概没那么多
Probably not that much.
如果是的话，你的公司是否给你一个采访人的课程 ?
If at all, does your company give you
a course on how to interview people?
有些人有，有的没有。
Some do, some don't.
对比你花了几个小时来研究采访的时间。
Now contrast that against how many hours
you've spent studying the interview.
那里有个断开的地方
Hm, there's a disconnect somewhere.
我不知道为什么面试这么艰难
I wonder why interviews are so hard.
因为我们很注重通过面试
Because we focus so
much on passing an interview, but
我们从没想过我们什么时候在桌子的另一边
we never think about when we're
on the other side of the table.
为了创造这个课程，我和很多人交谈过。
And to create this course,
I talked to a lot of people.
我和 Netflix，谷歌和 Facebook 的人交谈。
I talk to people at Netflix,
and Google, and Facebook.
我和那些在小型创业公司工作的人交谈
And I talk to people who
work at small startups,
我和那些在中型创业公司工作的人交谈
I talk to people who work
at medium-sized startups.
我出去采访了
I went out and I interviewed,
我同意如果大家都知道有点不愉快但我去了
which I agree if we all know it's
a bit unpleasant, but I went on
因为我想知道哪些公司在问这几天。
an interview because I wanted to find out
what are companies asking these days.
他们想知道的问题的类型是什么 ?
What are the type of
questions they wanna know?
他们在工程师里找什么
What are they looking for in an engineer?
但我也想知道人们是怎么对待我的
But also I wanna know,
how did people treat me?
我喜欢什么
What did I like?
我不喜欢什么
What did I dislike?
我们从没想过这个
We never think about this.
那天我在推特上发过消息也许我会和你分享
I tweeted this out the other day and maybe
I'll share it with you at some point.
但这是典型的面试经验。
But here's a typical
interviewing experience.
走吧走吧
Walk in.
有人要求你执行，我不知道，
Someone asked you to implement,
I don't know,
一个白板上的二进制搜索树 [ SOUND ]
a binary search tree on the whiteboard and
already you're like, [SOUND] but
你这么做是因为你花了三个月的时间来面试
you did it because you spent three months
studying for this interview, and you pass.
你的感觉糟透了
You're like, that was terrible.
我不会那么做的那太可怕了
[LAUGH] I will never do that,
that was awful.
我很高兴我能通过我的提议现在我要去吃免费午餐了
I'm glad I got through, I got the offer,
now I'm going to eat my free lunch.
然后，六个月后，有人进来了，有点紧张。
And then, six months later,
someone comes in, a little nervous.
他们喜欢，欢迎加入 Acme Corp.
They're like, welcome to Acme Corp.
现在你知道我要你做什么了，我要你在白板上执行一个。
Now you know what I want you to do, I want
you to implement a on the whiteboard.
这是一个非常快速的查找素数的方法。
That's a very fast way of
finding prime numbers.
但你不会知道除非你研究
But you wouldn't know that unless
you study because it's not
每天都有你用的东西
something you use every day.
但这有点像大学的嗡嗡会
But it's kind of like University hazing.
这一切都糟透了但这个循环一直持续下去
It all sucks but the cycle just
keeps going and going and going.
因为我们忘记了在餐桌的另一边
Because we forget what it's like to
be on the other side of the table,
我们忘了基本的同情
we are forgetting that basic empathy.
所以我想从采访者的角度来看这个课程。
So I wanna tell this course from the
perspective of the interviewer as well.
听起来不错
Sound good, yeah.
我想挑战你回到你的工作地点
And I wanna challenge you to go
back to your place of work and
比如说我们怎么不去采访人呢 ?
say, how come we never study
how to interview people?
我们怎么能不能有这种普通的卢布呢
How can we not have this common rubric?
我想开始对话因为采访不是很棒
I wanna start that conversation
because interviewing is not great.
我想我们能搞定
I think we can fix it.